Hi all. Let's take some time to look at
the Cable Models Capstone project
sponsored by Los Alamos.
This project was conceived because the
work done by the New Hanford dry
retrieval effort. Work done involved use
of machinery in dangerous waste tanks.
The problem is that cable management
takes an unfortunate amount of
engineering time, which can attributes to
a lot of inefficiencies. So our
contracts - our contacts at Los Alamos
are very interested in seeing simulations
of cable behavior.
The first algorithm we considered was a
finite element deformation. This is a
precise solution utilizing non-linear
implicit solving. The other
solver we implemented uses mass spring
evaluation. This is a naive approach, but
it's very fast and easy to implement.
It serves very well for many different
applications. The application was
developed using Godot 4, an open source
game engine.
Now let's look at the program. Here's the
main scene where we can view the
structures generated. We have the ability
to view and generate these two
structures, mass spring and FEM
deformation. We can change parameters
such as mass, length, and start and end
position. We can also change the
stiffness and convergence thresholds and
add external forces if we wanted to.
In the statistics panel we can see the
amount of time it takes to do the
computations as well as the plot
comparison differences like mean squared
error. We can also save this to a file.
To consider our project evaluation, let's
look at user testing. We had responses
from 5 engineers and researchers at Los
Alamos. They gave us open-ended feedback
as well as Likert scale responses. We
also had to perform many internal checks
for stability as we developed.
In the future, we expect this project to
expand to a 3D space with more intuitive
controls for forces and endpoint
placement. Collision and friction would
also be required for further research and
development. We feel that what our
sponsors really need is a focus on
decision-making components. We want to
develop methods to detect bad states when
managing cables. Thank
you very much and that's what we've
accomplished.